Guide to the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Numerical, 101-200, Series XV
  - No. 177: U.S. Army. Continental Army (Mass.), 1777-1783 (Box 82, Folder 1650)
  - No. 178: Staiff, Russell
    See: Alfred Bingham Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 148
  - No. 179: Ripley, S. Dillon
    See: S. Dillon Ripley Papers, Ms.Gr. No. 1066
  - No. 180: Coffey, Titian James, 1885, 1892 (Box 82, Folder 1651)
  - No. 181: Havana. Prefectura Principal de Policia, 1851-1869 (Box 82, Folder 1652)
  - No. 182: Mansfield, Giles, 1840 (Box 82, Folder 1653)
  - No. 183: Grimes, James Wilson, 1869 (Box 82, Folder 1654)
  - No. 184: Innes, Harry, 1804 (Box 82, Folder 1655)
  - No. 185: Gerry, Elbridge
  - No. 186: Lee, Thomas Sim, 1794 (Box 82, Folder 1657)
  - No. 187: Diamond, Peter Charles, 1974 (Box 82, Folder 1658)
  - No. 188: Edwards, Theodore D., 1863 (Box 82, Folder 1659)
  - No. 189: Dearborn, Henry Alexander Scammell, 1808-1810 (Box 83, Folder 1660)
  - No. 190: Villere, Jacques Philippe, 1826 (Box 83, Folder 1661)
  - No. 191: Havana. Siege. "Diario de el sitio y redicion de la plaza de la Habana al Ingles" by Pedro Juan Oeolanete, 1762 (Box 83, Folder 1662)
  - No. 192: Wilson, Henry, 1810 (Box 83, Folder 1663)
  - No. 193: Worth, Gorham A., 1823 (Box 83, Folder 1664)
  - No. 194: Shafter, William Rufus, 1900 (Box 83, Folder 1665)
  - No. 195: Woodbridge, William, 1820, 1841-1847 (Box 83, Folder 1666)
  - No. 196: Ness, Jesse, 1804 (Box 83, Folder 1667)
  - No. 197: Wood, Francis Carter, 1925 (Box 83, Folder 1668)
  - No. 198: Welles, Gideon, 1845 (Box 83, Folder 1669)
  - No. 199: Dennison, William, 1865, 1874 (Box 83, Folder 1670)
  - No. 200: Seward, William Henry, 1830-1866 (Box 83, Folder 1671)
- Numerical, 201-300, Series XVI
  - No. 201: Speed, James, 1882, undated (Box 84, Folder 1672)
  - No. 202: Harlan, James, 1865 (Box 84, Folder 1673)
  - No. 203: Fessenden, William Pitt, 1851 (Box 84, Folder 1674)
  - No. 204: Hallgarten, George Wolfgang Felix, [1933] (Box 84, Folder 1675-1682)
  - No. 204: Hallgarten, George Wolfgang Felix, [1933] (Box 85, Folder 1683-1684)
  - No. 205: Longenecker, David
  - No. 206: Smith, John Cotton, 1814 (Box 85, Folder 1686)
  - No. 207: Towson, Nathan, Circa 1844 (Box 85, Folder 1687)
  - No. 208: Porter, Moses, 1807 (Box 85, Folder 1688)
  - No. 209: Eustis, Jacob, 1812 (Box 85, Folder 1689)
  - No. 210: Shubrick, William Branford, 1847 (Box 85, Folder 1690)
  - No. 211: Denman, Charles L., 1854 (Box 85, Folder 1691)
  - No. 212: Burnet, William, 1721 (Box 85, Folder 1692)
  - No. 213: Eno, Henry, 1836 (Box 85, Folder 1693)
  - No. 214: Broun, Van, 1845 (Box 85, Folder 1694)
  - No. 215: Aldrich, Cyrus, 1865 (Box 85, Folder 1695)
  - No. 216: Stricker, John, 1800 (Box 85, Folder 1696)
  - No. 217: U.S. Military Academy, West Point, N.Y., 1813 (Box 85, Folder 1697)
  - No. 218: Ingraham, Joseph, 1790-1792 (Box 85, Folder 1698)
  - No. 219: Winder, William Henry, 1810, 1814 (Box 85, Folder 1699)
  - No. 220: Boudinot, Elias, 1783 (Box 85, Folder 1700)
  - No. 221: [Treaties]: "Abrégé des Principaux Traités...de l'Europe", undated (Box 85, Folder 1701-1702)
  - No. 222: Memminger, Charles Gustavus, 1861 (Box 86, Folder 1703)
  - No. 223: Colbert, William (Chief of the Chickasaws), 1822 (Box 86, Folder 1704)
  - No. 224: Parker, Daniel, 1820 (Box 86, Folder 1705)
  - No. 225: Larned, Benjamin Franklin, 1846 (Box 86, Folder 1706)
  - No. 226: Wilkinson, James, 1799, 1813 (Box 86, Folder 1707)
  - No. 227: Knox, Robert, 1840 (Box 86, Folder 1708)
  - No. 228: Leopold I, King of the Belgians, 1839 (Box 86, Folder 1709)
  - No. 229: Taylor, James
    See: Civil War MSS Collection, Ms. Gr. No. 619
  - No. 230: Chase, Salmon Portland, 1864 (Box 86, Folder 1710)
  - No. 231: Hunter, William, 1865 (Box 86, Folder 1711)
  - No. 232: Morgan, Edwin Dennison, 1861-1863 (Box 86, Folder 1712)
  - No. 233: Usher, John Palmer, 1852 (Box 86, Folder 1713)
  - No. 234: Watson, Philip Hill, 1863 (Box 86, Folder 1714)
  - No. 235: Stanton, Edwin McMasters, [ 1847?], 1851 (Box 86, Folder 1715)
  - No. 236: Morse, Abel, undated (Box 86, Folder 1716)
  - No. 237: Steele Family, 1802-1880 (Box 86, Folder 1717-1727)
  - No. 238: Antoine, Jacques, 1788 (Box 86, Folder 1728)
  - No. 239: Thomas, James, 1841 (Box 86, Folder 1729)
  - No. 240: Wrede, Karl Philip, 1831 (Box 86, Folder 1730)
  - No. 241: Smith, William Sydney, 1826, 1833 (Box 86, Folder 1731)
  - No. 242: Blacas d'Aulps, Pierre Louis Jean Casimir, due de, undated (Box 86, Folder 1732)
  - No. 243: Laurent, Paul Louis Marie, 1824 (Box 86, Folder 1733)
  - No. 244: Louis Antoine de Bourbon, due d'Angoulême, 1819 (Box 86, Folder 1734)
  - No. 245: Anderson, William Clayton, 1861 (Box 86, Folder 1735)
  - No. 246: Smith, Jeremiah, 1840 (Box 86, Folder 1736)
  - No. 247: Manning, Henry Edward, cardinal, 1887 (Box 86, Folder 1737)
  - No. 248: Lang, Louis
  - No. 249: Sparks, Jared, 1842 (Box 86, Folder 1739)
  - No. 250: Schiassi, Filippo, 1818 (Box 86, Folder 1740)
  - No. 251: Wassenaer, Jacob, baron van, heer van Obdam en Zuidwijk, 1661, undated (Box 86, Folder 1741)
  - No. 252: Peel, Robert, 1827 (Box 86, Folder 1742)
  - No. 253: Pius VII, pope
  - No. 254: Campbell, James, 1890 (Box 86, Folder 1744)
  - No. 255: Zuylen van Nyevelt, Philippus Julius van, 1771-1772, 1806-1827 (Box 86, Folder 1745)
  - No. 256: Blount, William, 1791, undated (Box 86, Folder 1746)
  - No. 257: Bloomfield, Joseph, 1813-1814 (Box 86, Folder 1747)
  - No. 258: McClellan, George Brinton, 1859 (Box 86, Folder 1748)
  - No. 259: Gaines, Edmund Pendleton, 1817 (Box 86, Folder 1749)
  - No. 260: Palmer, Thomas Witherell, 1889 (Box 86, Folder 1750)
  - No. 261: Mifflin, Thomas
  - No. 262: Le Compte, Benjamin, undated (Box 86, Folder 1752)
  - No. 263: Rutledge, John, 1818 (Box 86, Folder 1753)
  - No. 264: West, Stephen, 1814 (Box 86, Folder 1754)
  - No. 265: Martin, Augustus P., 1877 (Box 86, Folder 1755)
  - No. 266: Houseman, Julius, 1884 (Box 86, Folder 1756)
  - No. 267: Winans, Sarah (Atkinson), 1890 (Box 86, Folder 1757)
  - No. 268: Howard, Jacob Merritt, 1805 (Box 86, Folder 1758)
  - No. 269: Croswell, Charles Miller, 1877 (Box 86, Folder 1759)
  - No. 270: Jerome, David Howell, 1881 (Box 86, Folder 1760)
  - No. 271: Trowbridge, C. F., 1874 (Box 86, Folder 1761)
  - No. 272: Stone, J. H., 1873 (Box 86, Folder 1762)
  - No. 273: Morrison, A. H., 1873 (Box 86, Folder 1763)
  - No. 274: Loring, Joseph, Jr., 1815 (Box 86, Folder 1764)
  - No. 275: Barnard, E. L., 1857 (Box 86, Folder 1765)
  - No. 276: Lambert, Samuel Waldron
    See: Samuel W. Lambert Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 939
  - No. 277: Archer, Frederick Scott, 1856-1859, 1889, undated (Box 87, Folder 1766)
  - No. 278: Hoxey, Thomas, 1836 (Box 87, Folder 1767)
  - No. 279: Spain. Ministerio de marina, 1785 (Box 87, Folder 1768)
  - No. 280: Cochrane, Thomas, 10th Earl of Dundonald, 1822-1839 (Box 87, Folder 1769)
  - No. 281: Vigilante (brig), undated (Box 87, Folder 1770)
  - No. 282: Lyon, Charles H., 1854 (Box 87, Folder 1771)
  - No. 283: Kempe, Alfred John, 1832 (Box 87, Folder 1772)
  - No. 284: Jürgensen, Jorgen, 1817 (Box 87, Folder 1773)
  - No. 285: Johnston, Alexander, 1847 (Box 87, Folder 1774)
  - No. 286: Potter, Woodburne, 1836-1840 (Box 87, Folder 1775)
  - No. 287: Haines, Thomas J., 1855 (Box 87, Folder 1776)
  - No. 288: Vincent, Thomas McCurdy, 1856 (Box 87, Folder 1777)
  - No. 289: United States Exploring Expedition, 1838-1842, 1841-1846, 1858 (Box 87, Folder 1778)
  - No. 290: [War of 1812]: Rye, N.Y., 1814-1816, undated (Box 87, Folder 1779)
  - No. 291: Baird, Lucy Hunter, 1888-1889 (Box 87, Folder 1780)
  - No. 292: Harrington, George, 1865 (Box 87, Folder 1781)
  - No. 293: Cameron, Simon, 1846 (Box 87, Folder 1782)
  - No. 294: Smith, Caleb Blood, 1860 (Box 87, Folder 1783)
  - No. 295: Courmant, Louis de Contenbeaux, 1893 (Box 87, Folder 1784)
  - No. 296: Cleveland, Livingston Warner, 1892-1916 (Box 87, Folder 1785)
  - No. 297: Scott, Robert Falcon
  - No. 298: Smith, Walter Bedell
    See: Walter B. Smith Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 388
  - No. 299: Tener, Hugh W.
  - No. 300: King, John Alsop
- Numerical, 301-400, Series XVII
  - No. 301: Waugh, Samuel Clark, 1969 (Box 88, Folder 1788)
  - No. 302: With a Rooster on the Shoulder, 1966 (Box 88, Folder 1789-1790)
  - No. 303: New York Bowery Fire Insurance Co.
    See: Ruggles Family Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 1199
  - No. 304: Rogers, James Gamble, Jr., 1942-1943 (Box 88, Folder 1791)
  - No. 305: Hawes, Joel
    See: David Daggett Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 162
  - No. 306: Cartwright, Eliza, 1804 (Box 88, Folder 1792)
  - No. 307: Converse, Eliza Nott, 1825 (Box 88, Folder 1793)
  - No. 308: Ross, David
  - No. 309: Beecher, Henry Ward, 1858 (Box 88, Folder 1795)
  - No. 310: Kissam, Daniel Whitehead
  - No. 311: Millar, Melville B., 1974 (Box 88, Folder 1796)
  - No. 312: Green, Jacob, 1839 (Box 89, Folder 1797)
  - No. 313: Bradlee, John D., 1860 (Box 89, Folder 1798)
  - No. 314: American Citizen, 1892 (Box 89, Folder 1799)
  - No. 315: Lusk family
  - No. 316: Adams, Andrew, [1774?] (Box 89, Folder 1800)
  - No. 317: Chittenden, Lucius Eugene, Circa 1879 (Box 89, Folder 1801)
  - No. 318: Ireland, Joseph Norton, 1891 (Box 89, Folder 1802)
  - No. 319: Ela, Jacob Hart, 1866 (Box 89, Folder 1803)
  - No. 320: Daniel, John Warwick, 1902 (Box 89, Folder 1804)
  - No. 321: O'Conor, Charles, 1865 (Box 89, Folder 1805)
  - No. 322: Tipton, Thomas Weston, 1852 (Box 89, Folder 1806)
  - No. 323: Totten, George Muirson, 1842 (Box 89, Folder 1807)
  - No. 324: Burke, Orville, 1867 (Box 89, Folder 1808)
  - No. 325: Hickenlooper, Andrew, 1871 (Box 89, Folder 1809)
  - No. 326: Ralston, John Campbell, 1854 (Box 89, Folder 1810)
  - No. 327: Long, Edward J. and Nathaniel R., 1822, 1828 (Box 89, Folder 1811)
  - No. 328: Brevoort, James Carson, 1871 (Box 89, Folder 1812)
  - No. 329: Female Society at Catskill, 1832 (Box 89, Folder 1813)
  - No. 330: Moreau, [John?] B. and C. C., 1859-1868 (Box 89, Folder 1814)
  - No. 331: Kelly family, 1831-1872 (Box 89, Folder 1815)
  - No. 332: Pezant, John L., and Company, 1841 (Box 89, Folder 1816)
  - No. 333: Allen, Wiliam Richard, 1974-1975, undated (Box 89, Folder 1817)
  - No. 334: Durand, élie Magloire, 1831 (Box 89, Folder 1818)
  - No. 335: Rolft, William James, undated (Box 89, Folder 1819)
  - No. 336: Griswold, Almon W., 1887 (Box 89, Folder 1820)
  - No. 337: Hamilton, Alexander and James Alexander, 1828-1831 (Box 89, Folder 1821)
  - No. 338: Ely, Nathaniel, family, 1786-1829 (Box 89, Folder 1822)
  - No. 339: Munger, Timothy H., 1838 (Box 89, Folder 1823)
  - No. 340: [Anonymous]: draft of a letter to an editor, undated (Box 89, Folder 1824)
  - No. 341: Powdermaker, Hortense, 1950, 1954 (Box 89, Folder 1825)
  - No. 342: Moseley, Nicholas, 1969 (Box 89, Folder 1826)
  - No. 343: Osokin, Aleksandr Vasil'evich, 1974, undated (Box 89, Folder 1827)
  - No. 344: Elliot, Ely Augustus, 1844-1849 (Box 89, Folder 1828)
  - No. 345: Clift, Ethel Fogg and William Brooks
    See: E. F. and W. B. Clift Collection, Ms. Gr. No. 817
  - No. 346: Customs documents [l761?], 1798-1843 (Box 89, Folder 1829)
  - No. 347: Gerry, Samuel S., 1830-1831 (Box 89, Folder 1830)
  - No. 348: Tufele-Faia'oga, 1960 (Box 89, Folder 1831)
  - No. 349: Paine, Robert Treat, 1863 (Box 89, Folder 1832)
  - No. 350: Baldwin, Henry and James William, 1848, 1826-1830 (Box 89, Folder 1833)
  - No. 351: [Dame, William A.?]: "The Journey-man Mechanic's and Day-Laborer's Account Book", [1891-1893?] (Box 90, Folder 1834)
  - No. 352: Fitzpatrick, Thomas, 1796 (Box 90, Folder 1835)
  - No. 353: Ball, George Wildman, 1961-1962 (Box 90, Folder 1836)
  - No. 354: Rusk, Dean, 1961-1963 (Box 90, Folder 1837)
  - No. 355: Berle, Adolf Augustus, 1961 (Box 90, Folder 1838)
  - No. 356: [Kennedy Administration], 1961-1962 (Box 90, Folder 1839)
  - No. 357: Sisson, Edgar Grant, 1931, 1941 (Box 90, Folder 1840-1846)
  - No. 358: New York (City). Chamber of Commerce of the State of New York, undated (Box 90, Folder 1847)
  - No. 359: Trumbull, Jonathan, 1799-1800 (Box 90, Folder 1848)
  - No. 360: Findlay, James, 1802 (Box 90, Folder 1848)
    [Missing, 1980]
  - No. 361: Fisher, Irving Norton, 1976 (Box 90, Folder 1849)
  - No. 362: Onassis, Jacqueline (Bouvier) Kennedy, 1962-1965 (Box 90, Folder 1850)
  - No. 363: Van Buskirk, Arthur B., 1943 (Box 90, Folder 1851)
  - No. 364: Ely, William, 1833 (Box 90, Folder 1852)
  - No. 365: Graham, James Duncan, 1842-1843, undated (Box 90, Folder 1853)
  - No. 366: Litchfield, Luther, 1844 (Box 90, Folder 1854)
  - No. 367: Knowlton, Captain, 1812 (Box 91, Folder 1855)
  - No. 368: Goltz, Erich, [ca. 1932?] (Box 91, Folder 1856)
  - No. 369: [Michigan]: John Stoughton Newberry and Peter White, 1883, 1906 (Box 91, Folder 1857)
  - No. 370: Lafountain, Sarah, 1762 (Box 91, Folder 1858)
  - No. 371: Nock, Albert Jay, 1940 (Box 91, Folder 1859)
  - No. 372: Huntington, Ebenezer, 1810 (Box 91, Folder 1860)
  - No. 373: Webster, Noah, 1781, 1783 (Box 91, Folder 1861)
  - No. 374: McDannel, Thomas Humes, 1912-1924 (Box 91, Folder 1862)
  - No. 375: Byrd, Richard Evelyn, 1936 (Box 91, Folder 1863)
  - No. 376: Le Texier, 1776 (Box 91, Folder 1864)
  - No. 377: [Discarded, 1982] (Box 91, Folder --)
  - No. 378: Pennsylvania. Governor (James A. Beaver)
  - No. 379: Doran, James
  - No. 380: Hay, Udney, 1794 (Box 91, Folder 1865)
  - No. 381: Long, Huey Pierce, 1933 (Box 91, Folder 1866)
  - No. 382: Hubbard, Mary Brown, 1826-1843 (Box 91, Folder 1867)
  - No. 383: Service, Caroline Edward (Schulz), 1976-1978 (Box 91, Folder 1867A)
  - No. 384: Chandler family, 1741-1846, undated (Box 91, Folder 1867B)
  - No. 385: Law family, 1834-1886 (Box 91, Folder 1867B)
  - No. 386: Loney, Alice (Allen), 1863-1864 (Box 91, Folder 1868)
  - No. 387: The Zealandia "Star", 1888 (Box 91, Folder 1869)
  - No. 388: Yucatec manuscripts, [1629?], undated (Box 91, Folder 1870)
  - No. 389: Graham, Eliza, 1831-1832 (Box 91, Folder 1871)
  - No. 390: Brush, Edward, and miscellaneous, 1802, 1816, undated (Box 91, Folder 1872)
  - No. 391: Sherman, William Tecumsah, 1869, 1874 (Box 91, Folder 1873)
  - No. 392: Sprague Family Papers, 1766-1830 (Box 92, Folder 1874)
  - No. 393: Cohen, Elliot Ettelson, 1930-1959 (Box 92, Folder 1875-1876)
  - No. 394: Gregg, Thomas, 1861-1890 (Box 92, Folder 1877)
  - No. 395: National Liberal League, 1879 (Box 92, Folder 1878)
  - No. 396: New Haven Bicentennial Medal, 1838-1842 (Box 92, Folder 1879-1880)
  - No. 397: Brown, Charles William, [1877?] (Box 92, Folder 1881)
  - No. 398: Middlesex County (Conn.) Congregational Church. Committee of the Association of the County of Middlesex, 1808 (Box 92, Folder 1882)
  - No. 399: Vinton, Francis, 1846-1856 (Box 92, Folder 1883)
  - No. 400: McGuire, James C., 1853 (Box 92, Folder 1884)
- Numerical, 401-500, Series XVIII
  - No. 401: Govett, William G., 1818-1839 (Box 93, Folder 1885)
  - No. 402: Morton, Benjamin Alexander, 1923-1927, undated (Box 93, Folder 1886)
  - No. 403: White, Wallace Humphrey, Jr., 1935-1952, undated (Box 93, Folder 1887)
  - No. 404: Adams, Charles Christopher, 1909-1912 (Box 93, Folder 1888)
  - No. 405: Hall, Lovell, 1872-1874 (Box 93, Folder 1889)
  - No. 406: Whitmore, Mrs. O. H., 1882 (Box 93, Folder 1890)
  - No. 407: Burnap, D. H., 1839 (Box 93, Folder 1891)
  - No. 408: Bacon, Libbie, 1855-1860 (Box 93, Folder 1892)
  - No. 409: Douglass, Permilla, 1832-1885 (Box 93, Folder 1893)
  - No. 410: Shapter, Ann E., 1829-1838, 1873 (Box 93, Folder 1894)
  - No. 411: Pleasants, Ann E., 1829-1836 (Box 93, Folder 1895)
  - No. 412: Kondakov, Nikodim Pavlovich, 1909, 1941 (Box 94, Folder 1896)
  - No. 413: Palmer, Job, 1683, 1739, 1743, 1800, undated (Box 94, Folder 1897)
  - No. 414: Committee of the Proprietors of Common and Undivided Lands in the Town of New Haven (Box 94, Folder 1897)
    - 1723-1749 (Box 94, Folder 1898)
    - 1749-1927 (Box 95, Folder 1899-1900)
  - No. 415: Judd, Frances H., 1981 (Box 95, Folder 1901)
  - No. 416: Livingston, Peter R., 1763 (Box 95, Folder 1902)
  - No. 417: Wilson, Andrew, 1843-1870, undated (Box 95, Folder 1903)
  - No. 418: Clinton Stamp Club, Clinton, Conn. (re: Abraham Pierson and Elihu Yale), 1974 (Box 95, Folder 1904)
  - No. 419: Bache, Alexander Dallas, 1780-1863 (Box 95, Folder 1905)
  - No. 420: Franco Bahamonde, Francisco, 1939 (Box 95, Folder 1906)
  - No. 421: Jay's treaty, 1794, 1794-1795, undated (Box 95, Folder 1907)
  - No. 422: Baltimore, Battle of, 1814, 1841 (Box 95, Folder 1908)
  - No. 423: Oberlin-Wellington Rescue, 1858, 1859, 1930 (Box 95, Folder 1909)
  - No. 424: Hyde, John, 1790 (Box 95, Folder 1910)
  - No. 425: Furman, John
  - No. 426: Oneida County, N.Y.
  - No. 427: Hall, John, 1730 (Box 95, Folder 1911)
  - No. 428: Fuller, Margaret, [1842?] (Box 95, Folder 1912)
  - No. 429: Dumas, Alexandre, undated (Box 95, Folder 1913)
  - No. 430: Magnus, Charles, undated (Box 95, Folder 1914)
  - No. 431: Seely, Jane, Circa 1827-1836 (Box 95, Folder 1915)
  - No. 432: Earle, Alice Morse (re: William and Mary (Burnet) Browne of Salem), 1903 (Box 95, Folder 1916)
  - No. 433: Jesup, Thomas Sidney, 1819 (Box 95, Folder 1917)
  - No. 434: Rathbone, Thomas W., 1801 November 21 (Box 95, Folder 1918)
  - No. 435: Pamphlets, E. Cady Stanton (1854) and Wendell Phillips (1859) (re: women's rights), 1854; 1859 (Box 95, Folder 1919)
  - No. 436: Walter Lippman commemorative stamp (black and white print; color transparency), 1985 (Box 95, Folder 1920)
  - No. 437: Cameron, Norman to Niederlander, William C., 1972 (Box 96, Folder 1921)
  - No. 438: Camp des Milles (photocopies), undated (Box 96, Folder 1922)
  - No. 439: Booker T. Washington to Morris Tyler, 1901 (Box 96, Folder 1923)
  - No. 440: Regular National Democratic Nominations list for President (Stephen A. Douglas), for Vice President (Herschel V. Johnson); presidential electoral ticket, undated (Box 96, Folder 1924)
  - No. 441: The Liberal Jewish Congregation of Liverpool; correspondence of Raphael Levine, 1938 August 1 (Box 96, Folder 1925)
  - No. 442: Leo Lesquereux; correspondence, biographical material, 1861, 1874 1890, 1934 (Box 96, Folder 1926)
  - No. 443: Journal by unknown author describing the political situation in South America, particularly in Venezuela, 1824 December 15-1828 November 11 (Box 96, Folder 1927)
  - No. 444: John Angel; correspondence, Christmas greetings, 1953-1959, undated (Box 96, Folder 1928)
  - No. 445: "Quaint Advertisements of Bygone Days: Reproductions of Announcements Printed During the Period 1704-1832", by William H. Jackson, [1920] (Box 97, Folder 1929)
  - No. 446: Magnes, Judah L.: address and article [from the library of Arthur A. Cohen], 1947-1948 (Box 98, Folder 1930)
  - No. 447: Three postage stamps commemorating the death of Czechoslovakian freedom fighters, 1991 (Box 98, Folder 1931)
  - No. 448: Collection of eight handwritten documents regarding the Jewish population in Paris at the end of the eighteenth and the beginning of the nineteenth centuries (in Hebrew), Circa 1800 (Box 98, Folder 1932)
  - No. 449: Anonymous journal of an American traveller in England, France, and Turkey, 1851 (Box 98, Folder 1933)
  - No. 450: Focillon, Henri: "L'Art de Piranesi," [writing in French], undated (Box 98, Folder 1934)
  - No. 451: Smith, Sarah D. Abbot: travel journal kept while on trip from New Hampshire to Pennsylvania, 1828 July 20-August 9 (Box 98, Folder 1935)
  - No. 452: "Christ Church": loose pages describing Episcopal Church service, undated (Box 98, Folder 1936)
  - No. 453: Untitled short story by unknown author, undated (Box 98, Folder 1937)
  - No. 454: Lemcke, Ernest Gustave: "The Tribal Hidage. The Early History of Wessex (494-593 A.D.). The Burghal Hidage and the County Hidages,", undated (Box 98, Folder 1938)
  - No. 455: Grand Army Fair, New Haven: exhibition catalog of war relics loaned for fair, 1887 December (Box 98, Folder 1939)
  - No. 456: Baile, Marion: "The Old Willow Stump and Other Poems" [includes letter from William Lyon Phelps], 1915 (Box 98, Folder 1940)
  - No. 457: Yiddish theater in Poland: eleven posters, 1986, undated (Box 98, Folder 1941)
  - No. 458: Manifestos (14) of the Old Yishuv in Jerusalem, [concerning religious, economic, and administrative matters affecting Jews living in Palestine, specifically Jerusalem], Circa1910-1941 (Box 98, Folder 1942)
    See:Box 100
  - No. 459: Cost of living charts of Richmond T. and Caroline M. Roberts of Hamden, CT, 1927-1957, 1959, 1963-1966; Poole family genealogy (Box 98, Folder 1943)
  - No. 460: New Haven Arms Company: Volcanic Repeating-Fire Arms advertisement, 1860, and pamphlet, "Henry's Repeating Rifle, 1863 (Box 98, Folder 1944)
  - No. 461: Westminster Shorter Catechism [facsimile of], 1888 (Box 98, Folder 1945)
  - No. 462: "The Honorable Gerhard A. Gesell," bound copy of interview conducted as part of the oral history project of the Historical Society of the District of Columbia Circuit, 1998 (Box 98A, Folder 1946)
  - No. 463: Bowles, Edward Augustus: letters by and about E. A. Bowles pertaining to gardening and plants, 1924, 1927 (Box 98A, Folder 1947)
  - No. 464: Naval School Hospital: "The Knapsack," handwritten manuscript of short essays and poetry, vol. 1, no. 1, "edited by the Ladies,", 1863 November 3 (Box 98A, Folder 1948)
  - No. 465: "Genealogy of the Family of Symington in Scotland" [printed chart tracing the family from pre-1300s; included is Symington family in New Jersey, U.S.A.], undated (Box 98A, Folder 1949)
  - No. 466: DVD of the "Tribute in Light" memorial at the World Trade Center site, New York City, 2002 March 11 (Box 98A, Folder 1950)
  - No. 467: "Orders and Articles Granted By The High and Mightie Lords, The States General Of The United Provinces, Concerning the Erecting of a West India Companie: Together with the Priviledges and rights given unto the same" [handwritten twenty-two page manuscript containing forty-five orders and articles relating to the formation of the Dutch West India Company], 1621 (Box 98A, Folder 1951)
  - No. 468: "Kronika Rodzinna: Czesc pierwsza Do 1958 roku," by Marek Skwarnicki [family chronicle through 1958: accompanied by correspondence on postcard], 1958, 1998 (Box 98A, Folder 1952)
  - No. 469: Tolstoy, Mary (daughter of Leo Tolstoy): letter to Mrs. F. J. Stetson thanking her for books sent to her father, 1890 April 18 (Box 98A, Folder 1953)
  - No. 470: Robertson, George B.: letter to Richard Sheppard concerning the sale of a meadow to George Rumsey, 1868 January 15 (Box 98A, Folder 1954)
  - No. 471: Penn, William: Portion of letter written by Penn to James Logan ["Secretary to the Government of Pensilvania in America"; published in Correspondence between William Penn and James Logan; ed. Edward Armstrong. Philadelphia, 1870-1872. Typed transcription included], 1703 October 7 (Box 98A, Folder 1955)
  - No. 472: Publicity photograph, black and white, for the film So Proudly We Hail, Paramount Pictures, Inc., 1943 (Box 98A, Folder 1956)
  - No. 473: Photograph of Company A depicts a group of young men in uniform, names and ranks on back of photograph, Undated (Box 98A, Folder 1957)
  - No. 474: Facsimiles of a Tomas Maldonado manuscript and a folder with two pockets containing cards depicting reproduced works by Maldonado., 1948 (Box 98A, Folder 1958)
  - No. 475: Three Italian travel posters, 1923
    See: Box 101
  - No. 476: Photograph of "Officers of the American Historical Association" with original backing and negative, 1889 December 30
    See: Box 102
  - No. 477: Photograph of Sun Yat-sen (commonly known as the "father of Modern China") and his letter to Francis W. Damon, president of the Mid-Pacific Institute, 1912 February 8
    See: box 103
  - No. 478: Bassett, J. Walter and Evangeline Cunningham Bassett